<feed>
 <entry>
		<title>Parisians in the Country</title>
		<author>Honoré de Balzac</author>
		<link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/honore-de-balzac</link>
		<published>2025-06-04T20:21:14Z</published>
		<updated>2025-06-04T20:21:16Z</updated>
		<summary>Gaudissart is a traveling salesman, well-known, well-respected, and universally considered to be one of the best—hence his nickname of Gaudissart the Great. As he enters a small town, he enlists the help of one of the town's notables. The notable, who's not as impressed by Gaudissart's sales pitch as Gaudissart thinks he is, sends Gaudissart to another well-known man of the town, and the resulting encounter is one of Balzac's more humorous episodes. In The Muse of the Department, a superior woman in Sancerre is married to a man interested only in money. She has been pursued for years by three local men, all of whom she puts off, not feeling any are up to her standards. When a journalist from Paris makes his appearance and shows an interest in her—which she avidly returns—the scene is set for someone's comeuppance; but exactly whose remains unclear for most of the story.</summary>
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>The Autobiography of an Idea</title>
		<author>Louis H. Sullivan</author>
		<link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/louis-h-sullivan</link>

		<published>2025-06-03T20:32:13Z</published>
		<updated>2025-06-03T20:35:50Z</updated>
		<summary>Louis Sullivan was one of the most important architects working at the turn of the 20th century. His most well-known work was done in Chicago as part of the firm of Adler and Sullivan, but he also designed well-regarded buildings in cities like Philadelphia, St. Louis, and Buffalo. He has been called both the father of the skyscraper and the father of modernism, as well as being the progenitor of the famous maxim form follows function.Building in the seething crucible of progress that was post-fire Chicago, Sullivan put that famous maxim—the idea of his autobiography—to use by creating forms and grammars for the new kinds of high-rise buildings made possible by the newly-invented technique of steel-frame construction. But contrary to the impression of sparse minimalism that the mid-century Bauhaus movement brought to form follows function, Sullivan's building were often intricately decorated, with organic Beaux-Arts and Art Nouveau ornaments gracing their richly-designed façades. This book, his autobiography, was commissioned by the journal of the American Institute of Architects. Sullivan accepted the commission in part due to the financial difficulties he had encountered later in life; it was first published serially, then as a book, in 1922. Sullivan died just two years later.</summary>
		
	</entry>
	<entry>
		<title>The Columbiad</title>
		<author>Joel Barlow</author>
		<link>https://standardebooks.org/ebooks/joel-barlow</link>
		<published>2025-06-02T19:41:57Z</published>
		<updated>2025-06-02T19:43:48Z</updated>
		<summary>The Columbiad is an epic poem that celebrates America. It opens with Christopher Columbus in prison, despondent and feeling poorly rewarded for his great achievements. He is visited by Hesper, represented as the guardian genius of the lands to the west of Europe. He leads Columbus in a vision of the western hemisphere: its physical description, its native people, and the history of North and South America. They see the Aztec and Inca empires, the settling of America by Europeans, and the development of the British colonies up through the Revolutionary War and the founding of the United States.</summary>
	</entry>
</feed>
